Daniel Kiragu

P.O BOX 175

Njoro

+254 799 862 659

danielmburu674@gmail.com

https://github.com/Dantiff

OBJECTIVE

To work in a modern and dynamic organization or institution that encourages professionalism and development; helping it achieve its own vision and mission by promoting creativity and innovativeness

SKILLS

Programming Languages

- Front-end Processing: Excellent in HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript (JQuery) and JS frameworks including VueJS and AngularJS.
- Back-end processing: Excellent in OOP PHP with the Laravel framework and OOP Python with the Django framework.
- Database management: MySQL and PgSQL
- Familiar with: C, C++, JavaSOFTWARE AND TECHNOLOGIES

Software and Hardware Technologies

- Platform: Microsoft Windows, Ubuntu Linux, Mac OSx
- Databases: MS Access, PgSQL, and MySQL.
- Hardware: PC repair and maintenance, PC networking.
- Communication: slack, skype, watsapp and other preferred social media sites.
- VCS tools: git (Github and Bitbucket).
- Application Development and Deployment: Vagrant, Nginx, Homestead, Forge, FortRabbit, PHPStorm,
 Sublime, mailtrap.
- Application communication and Security: Rollbar, Mandril, Sendgrill, Authy, OpenConnect-OpenID, Google OAuth.

Software Development Methodologies

- Agile and scrum
- Waterfall

Information Technology Management

- Server configuration.
- Endpoint security and firewalls setup.
- Router and switch configuration.
- MPLS links setup and configuration.
- Printers and PBx phone setup, configuration, and support.

EXPERIENCE

May 2017 - To Date

Freelance Web Developer

- Development and deployment of web-based applications for proprietary clients.
- I have been using PHP and Python as the primary development languages.

May 2016 - April 2017 Cytonn Investments P.O BOX 20695 - 0200, Nairobi, Kenya

Software Engineer

- I have created and deployed financial and investments web-based applications that are used in the company on a daily basis.
- I have been trusted with managing confidential corporate information and property since I handle sensitive data on a daily basis.
- I also have been included as part of the management team where am currently managing an ongoing internship class for Software Engineers.

May 2015 - August 2015 Kenya Civil Aviation Authority (KCAA) P.O. Box 30163 -00100 Nairobi

Telecommunication and Support Services Intern

Assembly of computer equipment including printers, internet services, and phone services as well as
provisioning of IT support to fellow corporate employees.

May 2013 - August 2013 High Vision Computer Training College P.O BOX 78 Egerton

Computer Packages Tutor

 I taught the Eight Basic Computer Packages where I was able to improve my skills both on sociability and computer literacy.

May 2012 - To Date Orders Write and Code

Freelance Researcher

• I gained professional experience in customer servicing as well as boasting my abilities in information research and self-driven quality production.

Jan 2012 - August 2012 Kikapu secondary school

Peer teacher

 Received first hand mentor-ship on professional training and peer-to-peer mentor-ship that proved very important on personal growth on both social and professional levels.

EDUCATION

Sept 2012 - May 2016 Laikipia University P.O BOX 40 Nyahururu

Bsc. Computer Science

Second Class Honour Upper Division

Jan 2016 - May 2016 Laikipia University P.O BOX 40 Nyahururu

Cisco Certification: Cyber Security

Jan 2016 - May 2016 Laikipia University P.O BOX 40 Nyahururu

Cisco Certification: IOE

Jan 2016 - May 2016 Laikipia University P.O BOX 40 Nyahururu

Cisco Certification: A+

Jan 2012 - Feb 2012 St. Augustine Computer Training College P.O BOX 78 Egerton

Computer Packages

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I have a career aspiration to leverage strong academic and professional knowledge in your organization that will enhance the use of learned and acquired skills in endeavor to offer quality services and contribute significantly to your overall strategic goals and objectives.

VALUES

- · Ambitious, self-motivated, hardworking and committed to results and excellent performance.
- Ability to plan and implement tasks. Highly developed interpersonal and communication skills, creative and goal-driven, team player.
- Great presentation and problem solving skills.

- Paying attention to details.
- Follow Agile and Scrum to the letter.

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

- I am a highly-motivated and results orientated Application Programmer, practiced in the design and
 implementation of socioeconomic development, capacity building and technical assistance programs in both
 mobile and web-based applications. I hold a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and am currently in
 pursuit to expand my skills as a software engineer.
- In the field of IT engineering, my experience has also allowed me to interact with various hardware and network devices, making me a professional in ideal hardware operation and repair. I also have received training in networks configuration, monitoring, and management as well as in projects planning, scheduling, and management using management tools such as Open Workbench and COCOMO.

Referees

• Mr. Mwaruwa Chaka

mchaka@cytonn.com, +254 738 210 720 Senior Software Engineer/Supervisor Cytonn Investments.

Mr. Musonye Felix

fmusonye@kcaa.co.ke, +254 722 799 423 Senior Telecommunications Officer/Supervisor Kenya Civil Aviation Authority.

• Pastor Njuguna

+254 722 399200
Pastor and Spiritual Leader.
Full Gospel Churches of Kenya,
Njoro.